(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
You make me happy
夜空メル 5周年 LIVE
Yozora Mel 5th Anniversary LIVE
ゲスト多数！告知あり！
Many guests! Announcements included!
1st Anniversary
YOZORA MEL
2nd Anniversary
2020 birthday
3rd Anniversary
YOZORA MEL 2021
precious memories
4th Anniversary
YOZORA MEL 2022
Twinkle Starry Night
2022 Birthday
YOZORA MEL
-Halloween Princess-
5th Anniversary
YOZORA MEL 2023
白いドレス　花の冠
A white dress and a flower crown
世界一の愛を誓う
I vow the greatest love in the world
愛に出会い恋は続く
作詞・作曲 HoneyWorks
Meeting Love and Love Continues
Lyrics & Composition: HoneyWorks
みんなの中で一番綺麗
The most beautiful of all
君の不意打ち
Your unexpected move...
意地悪な人
...you tease.
いつもよりカッコいいかも
You might be cooler than usual.
気のせいですか？
Is it just my imagination?
二人は笑う
The two of us laugh.
紹介したい人がいるの
There's someone I want to introduce.
パパと同じ負けず嫌いな
Just like Papa, they're competitive,
涙脆くよく笑う
easily moved to tears, laughs a lot,
優しい人なんです
and they're a kind person.
歩いてもいいですか？
May I walk with you?
エスコートしてよね
Escort me, okay?
君はギュッと離さないでね
Hold me tight and don't let go.
世界一の愛をあげる
I'll give you the greatest love in the world.
喧嘩しても
Even if we fight,
落ち込んでも
even if I'm feeling down,
君の味方
I'm on your side.
愛に
In love
出逢い
meeting,
意味で
by its
逢う
meaning
君がいるな
you are here,
恋は続く
and love continues.
運命の糸はあくる日
The red thread of fate, the following day,
白馬に乗ってやってきました
arrived riding on a white horse.
現実はそうじゃないけれど
Reality isn't quite like that, but
普通の君が一番好きよ
I like the ordinary you the best.
紹介したい人がいます
There is someone I want to introduce.
ついつい 止まらない
I can't help but go on and on.
君 緊張して噛んじゃうの
You're getting nervous and stumbling over your words.
来てくれてありがとう
Thank you for coming.
近づいてもいいですか？
May I come a little closer?
独り占めしないでね
Don't keep me all to yourself.
君のために歌っておいたの
I've sung this for your sake,
世界一のドレス姿
the most beautiful dress in the world.
小指の糸ほどけないよね
The thread on our pinkies won't unravel, right?
ぎゅっと強く愛を編んで
Knitting our love tightly and strongly.
君の隣
By your side,
恋は続く
love continues.
笑ってて欲しかったの
I wanted you to keep on smiling.
パパの涙 溢れちゃうじゃん
Papa's tears are going to overflow.
君は凛として笑い
You smile with such dignity.
幸せをありがとう
Thank you for the happiness.
目を閉じていいですか？
May I close my eyes?
大好きでいてよね
Please keep on loving me.
君じゃないと 離さないでね
If it's not you... don't let go.
世界一の愛をあげる
I'll give you the best love in the world.
喧嘩しても
Even if we fight,
落ち込んでても
or if we feel down,
君の味方
I'm on your side,
愛に出会う
meeting love.
君がいるな
Since you are here,
恋は続く
love continues.
というわけで、
And so,
こんかぷー！
Konkapu!
魔界の天才ヴァンパイア、
The genius vampire from the Underworld,
夜空メルでーす！
I'm Yozora Mel!
イェーイ！みんな盛り上がってますかー？
Yay! Is everyone getting excited?
もうメルがホロライブに来てから、5年目みたいなんです。
It seems it's already been 5 years since I joined Hololive.
いやー、なんか早いようでね、長いようで、
Well, it feels both fast and long,
長いようで短い、ってやつなんですけども。
like one of those long-yet-short kinds of things.
なのでね、今回もいっぱい歌って踊るので、
So, I'm going to sing and dance a lot this time too,
最後まで楽しんでいってください！
so please enjoy until the very end!
見ててね、ゲストもこの後、たくさんね、お呼びしてるので、
Stay tuned, because I've invited many guests later,
楽しんでいってください！
so please look forward to it!
そして、今回もハッシュタグあります！
And we have a hashtag this time as well!
#夜空メル5周年 で、
With #YozoraMel5thAnniversary,
いっぱいスクショとか、ツイートとか、
I'd be happy if you take lots of screenshots
してくれると嬉しいな。
and tweet about it.
トレンドまで届いてほしいな、チラッ、チラッ。
I hope it reaches the trends... *glance* *glance*
よろしくお願いします！
Please support the stream!
それじゃあ、この後も、夜空メルをいっぱい見てってね！
Well then, please keep watching lots of Yozora Mel!
続きはウェブで！
The rest is on the web!
僕の名前はかぷ太郎。
My name is Kaputaro.
今日は魔界から来たヴァンパイア、夜空メルとデートである。
Today, I have a date with Yozora Mel, a vampire from the Underworld.
みてみて！めっちゃきれいじゃない？
Look, look! Isn't it really beautiful?
彼女が目を輝かせた先にあったのは ショーウィンドウに飾られた白い綺麗なドレスだった
What her eyes sparkled at was a beautiful white dress displayed in the shop window.
こういうの興味あるんだ？
Are you interested in this kind of thing?
んー、女の子なら一度は憧れるんじゃない？
Hmm, wouldn't every girl admire it at least once?
メルって黒のイメージあるじゃん？
Mel has an image of black, right?
こういう白いドレスも着てみたいな〜なんて！
I was thinking I'd like to try a white dress like this too!
(本音なのか照れ隠しなのか全く掴めない...が 彼女がドレスを着てみたいことだけはわかった。)
(I can't tell if she's being sincere or just shy... but I understood that she wants to try on the dress.)
...覚えとくよ。
...I'll remember that.
ん？今なんか言った？
Hmm? Did you say something?
(深夜アニメの主人公かな？立...)
(Am I a protagonist of a late-night anime? Stand...)
かぶ太郎：(深夜アニメの主人公かな？立場逆なんじゃ…と僕は心の中で突っ込んだ。)
Kabutarou: (Maybe I'm the protagonist of a late-night anime? Or is the roles reversed... I quipped in my mind.)
夜空メル：(本当は聴こえてたけどね…)
Yozora Mel: (In truth, I could hear you...)
愛してる 聞こえてる 君の番
I love you. Can you hear me? It's your turn.
愛してる
I love you.
風の日も 雨の日も
On windy days, on rainy days...
Ah
ずっとそばに
Stay by my side forever.
ミライチズ
作詞:MARUMOCHI BOYS
作曲:コミヤマリオ/MARUMOCHI BOYS
Mirai Chizu
Lyrics: MARUMOCHI BOYS
Composition: Komiyama Rio / MARUMOCHI BOYS
すれ違う金曜日 口をきかない土曜日
We passed each other on Friday, didn't talk on Saturday.
曖昧になってく理由
The reasons become ambiguous.
なんとなく戻って 日曜日「ごめんなさい」は
Somehow returning on Sunday, "I'm sorry"...
一緒に口にしてる
We say it together.
誰かが言っていた
Someone once said...
愛は譲り合うものらしい
Love is supposedly about compromise.
ほら ほら 言葉にしてよ
Come on, come on, put it into words.
もう一回
One more time.
愛してる 聞こえてる 君の番
I love you. Can you hear me? It's your turn.
愛してる
I love you.
風の日も 雨の日も ひと笑いしましょう
On windy days, on rainy days, let's share a laugh.
忘れないように 螺旋階段の夕焼け
So we don't forget, the sunset on the spiral staircase.
広くても 狭くなっても ずっとそばに居る
Whether it's wide or narrow, I'll be by your side forever.
君
You.
壊れかけていたインターホン 染みの付いた壁紙
The broken intercom, the stained wallpaper.
荷作り 重なった段ボール
Packing up, stacked cardboard boxes.
どこを切り取っても 思い出が蘇る
No matter where I look, memories come flooding back.
新居が楽しみだね
I'm looking forward to our new home.
誰かが言っていた
Someone once said...
幸福とは人を愛すること
Happiness is about loving someone.
ねえ ねえ 約束しよう
Hey, hey, let's make a promise.
永遠に
Forever.
愛してる 聞こえてる 君の番
I love you. Can you hear me? It's your turn.
愛してる
I love you.
病める日も 健やかなる日も ひと笑いしましょう
In sickness and in health, let's share a laugh.
この先何十年 繋がっていくミライチズ
Decades ahead, our 'Future Map' will keep connecting.
年を取っても 皺が増えても ずっとそばに居る
Even as we age and get more wrinkles, I'll be by your side forever.
君
You.
歌いたい 支えたい 見ていたい 歌いたい 甘えたい ふざけたい
I want to sing, support, and see; I want to sing, be spoiled, and goof around.
一緒に映画を見て泣きたい 君と
I want to watch a movie and cry with you.
この先何が起こったとして 変わらないことはただ一つ
No matter what happens in the future, there is only one thing that won't change.
君が好き
I love you.
愛してる 聞こえてる 君の番
I love you. Can you hear me? It's your turn.
愛してる
I love you.
風の日も 雨の日も ひと笑いしましょう
On windy days, on rainy days, let's share a laugh.
忘れないように 螺旋階段の夕焼け
So we don't forget, the sunset on the spiral staircase.
広くても 狭くなっても ずっと
Whether it's wide or narrow, forever...
愛してる 聞こえてる 君の番
I love you. Can you hear me? It's your turn.
愛してる
I love you.
病める日も 健やかなる日も ひと笑いしましょう
In sickness and in health, let's share a laugh.
この先何十年 繋がっていくミライチズ
Decades ahead, our 'Future Map' will keep connecting.
年を取っても 皺が増えても ずっとそばに居る
Even as we age and get more wrinkles, I'll be by your side forever.
君
You.
あー、ということでメル様、5周年おめでとう！
Ah, so with that, Mel-sama, congratulations on your 5th anniversary!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
いえー、めるちょこきっずですー！どもどもー。
Yay, it's MelChoco Kids! Hello, hello.
あ、ちょこ先生、せっかくベンチあるからさ、一緒に座らない？
Ah, Choco-sensei, since there's a bench here, why don't we sit together?
え、そんなメル様に誘っていただけるなんて光栄ですー！えー。
Eh, I'm so honored to be invited by Mel-sama like this!
踊って疲れたでしょ。
You're tired from dancing, right?
全然疲れてない。
I'm not tired at all.
あれ？じゃあ座ろうよ、せっかくだしさ。お花見しようよ、お花見。
Oh? Then let's sit down, since we're here. Let's do some cherry blossom viewing.
メル様とお花見できるのめちゃめちゃ嬉しい！やったー！
I'm so happy to be able to go cherry blossom viewing with Mel-sama! Yay!
よいしょ、よいしょ、よいしょ。あー。
Heave-ho, heave-ho. Ah.
おおー、桜綺麗だねー。
Oh, the cherry blossoms are beautiful.
きれい！
Beautiful!
ちょこ先生のほうがきれいだよ。
Choco-sensei is more beautiful.
え、そんなもんわかんないこと言わないでよ、メル様…もう！
Eh, don't say such confusing things, Mel-sama... really!
メル様桜に囲まれてちょっといつも以上に可愛い！
Mel-sama, surrounded by cherry blossoms, is even cuter than usual!
へへ、ありがとうちょこ先生。
Hehe, thank you, Choco-sensei.
あ可愛い！あちょっとファンサくださいほら。
Ah, cute! Hey, give me some fan service.
あいいよいいよ、あいいよいいよ、あふわめるちだなぁもう。
Ah, good, good. Ah, it's Mel-Mel fluffy... really.
ちょこ先生も…ほらちょこ様ももっとキスして。
Choco-sensei too... hey, Choco-sama, give more kisses.
ほらメル様足りない。
Hey Mel-sama, it's not enough.
んま！あははは、もう！嬉しい！
Mwah! Ahahaha, really! I'm happy!
ちょこ先生もっと近く行っていい？
Choco-sensei, can I go closer?
え？もっと近く？ちょっと遠いじゃん？
Eh? Closer? It's a bit far, right?
お？ほら一人分空いてるし。
Oh? Look, there's space for one person.
お？もしもし？もしもし？
Oh? Hello? Hello?
もうちょっと近く…ちょっと？じゃん！
A bit closer... wait? Ta-da!
ああああああ…
Ah, ah, ah, ah...
近い！近い！
Close! Close!
今スクリーンショットタイムだぞ。ドキドキ。
It's screenshot time now. My heart is pounding.
アニメが始まりそうである。
It looks like an anime is about to start.
うふ。エモい。
Ufu. Emotional.
エモいぞ。降下したわこうだな。
It's emotional. The outcome is like this.
ちょこ先生、実はさメルね、料理教室に最近通ってるんですよ。
Choco-sensei, actually, Mel has been attending cooking classes lately.
え、それははあちゃまの料理教室？
Eh, is that Haachama's cooking class?
はあちゃま？いやはあちゃまに料理習ったら料理じゃないんだよ。
Haachama? No, if you learn from Haachama, it's not cooking.
いや、だってメルメルクッキングもっと珍獣だな。
No, because Mel-Mel Cooking was more of a rare beast...
メルメルクッキングにしたかったチョコ…
I wanted to make it Mel-Mel Cooking, Choco...
珍獣ってなに？
What do you mean "rare beast"?
違うよ、普通の料理だよ。
No, it's normal cooking.
食べれる料理を作るってこと？
You mean making edible food?
食べれ…前も食べれてたわ！ガチ？へ？
Edible... it was edible before too! Seriously? Huh?
だってほら、ちょこ先生いつも誰かにさ作ってあげてるでしょ？
Because look, Choco-sensei is always making it for someone, right?
いやまあ確かにね。
Well, that's true.
だから今度はちょこ先生のためにメルが作ってさ、帰ってきたときにほら、ご飯あったら嬉しくない？
So next time Mel will make it for Choco-sensei, and when you come home, wouldn't you be happy if there was food?
え？ってことは…チョコが疲れて「あーただいま」って帰ってきて…
Eh? That means... Choco comes home tired saying "Ah, I'm home"...
したら「あれ？なんかいい匂いが」って言って、でリビング行ったらメル様が…
And then says "Huh? There's a nice smell", and then goes to the living room and Mel-sama is...
メル様が…？
Mel-sama is...?
そうだよ、「おかえりなさい」って。
That's right, "Welcome home".
「おかえりなさい」からの？からの？
From "Welcome home"...? And then? And then?
ご飯にする？
Do you want dinner?
ご飯にする？ああそうそうそっちね、お決まりの。
Do you want dinner? Ah right, that one, the standard.
お風呂にする？
Do you want a bath?
うん。
Yeah.
メルにする？
Do you want Mel?
いやもうそんなのご飯に決まってるじゃないですか！
No way, of course it's dinner!
メル様最高！おい！
Mel-sama is the best! Hey!
いやいい奥さんだそれはもうマジガチで！
No, that's a good wife, seriously for real!
やめてよ嬉しい…うふ。
Stop it, I'm happy... ufu.
やっぱ持つべきヴァンパイアね、やっぱメル様なのよ。
As expected, the vampire you should have is Mel-sama.
いやもうそれほどでも…ありがと。
No, not that much... thank you.
ちょこ先生今年はさ、一緒にお風呂入りませんか？
Choco-sensei, this year, why don't we take a bath together?
へ？お風呂…お…お…お風呂！お風呂！え？え？
Huh? Bath... b-b-bath! Bath! Eh? Eh?
だってめるちょこさ、もう結構長いじゃん付き合い。
Because Melchi-Choco, our relationship has been quite long already.
いやまあ確かに。
Well, that's true.
なのになのにお風呂も一緒に寝たこともないんだよ。
Yet we haven't taken a bath or slept together yet.
ああそうよね。うん。
Ah, that's right. Yeah.
え、今までお風呂入ったのって誰と？
Eh, who have you taken a bath with so far?
え…あ…こより。あぁこより様と。
Eh... ah... Koyori. Ah, with Koyori-sama.
スバルとも寝たけど、マリンとも寝たけど、まだちょこ先生と何もしてないんだよ。
I slept with Subaru, and I slept with Marine, but I haven't done anything with Choco-sensei yet.
そうですよね。そうだよ。
That's true. It is.
チョコはずっと待ってるのに。
Even though Choco has been waiting forever.
え待ってる？今年…だってそれ言ったらちょこ先生とはちゃんと時間作って一緒に…うん…するって言ったのに。
Eh, waiting? This year... because if you say that, I said I'd properly make time and do it with Choco-sensei...
あれ？メル待ちだったってこと？
Wait? You were waiting for Mel?
チョコずっと待ってたのに！
Even though Choco was waiting forever!
マジ？
Seriously?
ちょこ先生からも来ないよ。メルだって待ってるのに。
You don't come to me either, Choco-sensei. Even though Mel is waiting too.
本当に？
Really?
うん。
Yeah.
だってでもそしたら二番目の女…二番目の女？
But if so, then the second woman... the second woman?
チョコが一番だよ。
Choco is number one.
なにその顔。
What's with that face?
チョコ…チョコも一番の女になりたいからさ。
Choco... Choco wants to be the number one woman too.
え、ホロメンとはまだ旅行行ってない？
Eh, you haven't gone on a trip with Hololive members yet?
ああ行ってないかも。なんか大人数では行ったけどさ。
Ah, maybe not. We went in a large group, though.
二人の…二人の旅行は行ってない。行ってない。
A trip with just the two of us... just the two of us, we haven't gone. We haven't.
よーしゃ！今年めるちょこお泊り旅行行きます！
Alright! This year Melchi-Choco is going on an overnight trip!
やった！言質取りました！
Yay! I've got the promise!
やったー！
Yay!
あ、もうこんな時間だ。
Ah, it's already this time.
ちょっと待って、メルこのあとさ、用事があるんですよね。
Wait a second, Mel has something to do after this.
え誰と？
Eh, with whom?
え…あ…ねねちと。
Eh... ah... with Nenechi.
他の女と用事…
Having something to do with another woman...
あやっべ、ちょっとそろそろ行ってくるわ。
Ah, crap, I should probably get going soon.
じゃあめるちょこじゃあな！
Then Melchi-Choco, bye!
えちょっと待ってエロ！旅行まで決めてないよ！
Eh, wait, Ero! We haven't even decided on the trip yet!
可愛くてごめん
作詞・作曲：shito
Sorry for Being Cute
Lyrics/Composition: shito
私がいちばん私のこと愛して
I love myself the most,
何が悪いの？嫉妬でしょうか？
what's wrong with that? Is it jealousy?
痛いだとか、変わってるとか
"You're painful," "You're weird,"
届きませんね、その下げずみ
those sneers don't reach me.
大好きな お洋服で
In my favorite clothes,
大好きなお化粧で
with my favorite makeup...
お決まりの ハーフツインまいて
Curling my usual half-twin tails,
お出かけしよ 日傘持って
let's go out. Bringing my parasol...
望むだっけ 幸せだもん
it's because I'm happy.
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being cute.
生まれてきちゃってごめん
Sorry for being born.
Chu! あざとくてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being calculative.
気になっちゃうよね？ごめん
You're getting interested, right? Sorry.
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being cute.
努力しちゃっててごめん
Sorry for putting in effort.
Chu! 尊くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being precious.
女子力高くてごめん
Sorry for having high femininity.
ムカついちゃうよね？ざまぁｗ
You're getting annoyed, right? Serves you right!
あなたはあなたのことだけどうぞ
Please just worry about yourself.
私に干渉しないでください
Please don't interfere with me.
類は友を呼ぶと言うけど
They say "birds of a feather flock together,"
届きませんね、その陰口
but those backbitings don't reach me.
重い厚底ブーツ
With my heavy platform boots,
お気に入りのリュックで
with my favorite backpack...
崩せない 前髪 櫛でといて
My bangs that can't be messed up, combed out.
お出かけしよ 軽い女
Let's go out. "Easy girl"?
ふざけんな 重すぎるつの
Don't mess with me. I'm way too heavy.
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being cute.
この世に生きててごめん
Sorry for living in this world.
Chu! 目立っててごめん
Chu! Sorry for standing out.
意識しちゃうよね？ごめん
You can't help but notice, right? Sorry.
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being cute.
自分磨きしてごめん
Sorry for improving myself.
Chu! ぶりっ子でごめん
Chu! Sorry for acting like a coquette.
虜にしちゃってごめん
Sorry for captivating you.
ムカついちゃうでしょ？ざまぁｗ
You're getting annoyed, aren't you? Serves you right!
趣味の違い、変わり者と
Even if I'm made fun of for my different hobbies
馬鹿にされても
or being a weirdo...
曲げたくない、怖くもない
I don't want to change, and I'm not afraid.
あんたらこそ何？
What's up with you guys anyway?
自分の味方は自分でありたい
I want to be my own ally.
いちばん大切にしてあげたい
I want to treasure myself the most.
不条理な我慢をさせたくない
I don't want to make myself endure unreasonable things.
それが私！
That is me!
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being cute.
生まれてきちゃってごめん
Sorry for being born.
Chu! あざとくてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being calculative.
人生楽しんでごめん
Sorry for enjoying my life.
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being cute.
努力しちゃっててごめん
Sorry for putting in effort.
Chu! 尊くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being precious.
女子力高くてごめん
Sorry for having high femininity.
ムカついちゃうよね？ざまぁｗ
You're getting annoyed, right? Serves you right!
おねだりしてみてほしいの
I want you to try begging.
おねがいダーリン
作詞：ナナホシ管弦楽団 作曲：岩見 陸
Please Darling
Lyrics: Nanahoshi Orchestra Composition: Riku Iwami
とりあえずさぁ 私のこと全然聞かない
First of all, you don't listen to me at all!
あれほどやめてって言った タバコもお酒も毎日二箱・五合！
I told you so many times to stop... tobacco and alcohol every day, two packs and five go!
いい加減にして！お釈迦になっても、神は許してくれないんだからね！
Give it a rest! Even if you die, God won't forgive you!
あー、イヤイヤ。言うこと聞かないあなたのハートは真っ黒です！
Ah, no way. Your heart that doesn't listen to a thing is pitch black!
言いたいことは言わないし
You don't say what you want to say...
言いたい時からやりたいこともできてるくせして
even though you do whatever you want whenever you feel like it.
あんまりそんなのバカみたいじゃない？
Isn't that just a bit foolish?
そうじゃないじゃない、ちゃんと願えば今も！
That's not it, right? If you just wish properly, even now!
お互いのセブンを感じて
Feeling each other's "seven,"
察してほしい感じで
feeling like wanting to be understood...
わざと口にしないのズルくない？
Isn't it unfair not to say it out loud on purpose?
バカじゃないの？
Are you stupid?
おねがいダーリン 見て聞いて
Please, darling, look and listen.
ほしいのは形のないもの
What I want is something without shape.
バカにしないで 見て聞いて
Don't make fun of me, look and listen.
混ざり合え 瞳の奥の方
Blend together, deep in our eyes.
真っすぐ見つめて
Staring straight at me,
おねだりしてみてほしいの
I want you to try begging.
ダーリン 私はあなたの気持ちを全然知らないわ
Darling, I don't know your feelings at all.
あれほど手招きで見つめてきたのに今ではすっかり知らんぷり
I've been beckoning you with my gaze, yet you ignore me.
っていうかそれってあぐらかいてるだけなんじゃないですか？
I mean, aren't you just resting on your laurels?
ぶっちゃけした時三寸あなたのおかげで私のハートはボロボロです
To be frank, that distance has left my heart in tatters.
連れない時は忘れないし
I won't forget the times you're cold to me.
どっちがなかなか言い出さないからいつも私が貸し取り
Since neither of us speaks up, I'm always the one leading.
なんだかバカみたいじゃない
Doesn't it feel kind of stupid?
そう そんなことして何が楽しいの？
Yeah, what's so fun about acting like that?
どこか足元見てる感じで ラブみさるたる感じで
I feel like you're looking down on me, full of love-hate.
なにそれ 駆け引き？
What's that, some kind of tactic?
やーこっちも平静じゃなくなーい？
Hey, it's making me lose my cool too, you know?
そういうめんどくさいことしてるからめんどくさいことになるんだよ！
You're making things complicated with those games!
寡黙なダーリン見て聞いて
My silent Darling, look and listen.
刹那さは飾りじゃないのよ
This sadness isn't just for show.
よそ見しないで逃げないで
Don't look away, don't run away.
触ってよ心の奥の方
Touch the depths of my heart.
一瞬のことじゃない
It's not just for a moment.
おねだりしてはくれないの？
Won't you beg for me?
言葉にできない臆病さんば
An insecure person who can't find the words.
狡猾さではないのよ（隠さないで）
It's not about being clever. (Don't hide it)
甘えてないで口に出してよ
Don't hold back, say it out loud.
もう、ちゃんとこっち向いてったら！
Geez, I told you to look this way properly!
お願いダーリン見て聞いて
Please Darling, look and listen.
欲しいのは形のないもの
What I want is something intangible.
バカにしないわ見て聞いて
I won't make fun of you, look and listen.
覗いてよ瞳の奥の方
Peek into the depths of my eyes.
寡黙なダーリン寝てないで
My silent Darling, don't sleep.
甘えてよ私の素顔
Be spoiled by my true face.
お願いダーリンそばにいて
Please Darling, stay by my side.
触らせて心の奥の方
Let me touch the depths of your heart.
まっすぐ見つめて
Look at me straight.
おねだりしてみてほしいの
I want you to try begging for me.
お願いダーリン！
Please Darling!
イエーイ！
Yay!
魔界の天才バンパイア、ホロライブ1期生の夜空メルです！
The genius vampire from the underworld, Hololive 1st gen's Yozora Mel here!
えーと、ホロライブ界の天才バンパイア、えー、桃鈴ねねです！
And the genius vampire of the Hololive world, um, I'm Momosuzu Nene!
二人合わせて...
And together we are...
せーの、ねねメルねるねるねーるね！
Ready, go! Nene-Mel-Neru-Neru-Neru-ne!
完璧じゃん！ / いいじゃん！
That was perfect! / Not bad!
やったー！
We did it!
こないだのバカラライブで鍛えられたの。 / えー、すごい鍛えられて、楽しかったねー。
We got trained at that recent Baka-Live. / Yeah, we got trained hard, it was fun.
ねー。
Right?
で、メル先輩、5周年！
So, Mel-senpai, it's your 5th anniversary!
そうだよ、5周年だよー！ / すごーい！
That's right, 5 years! / Amazing!
イエーイ！
Yay!
なんか今回のロゴめっちゃ可愛い。なんかちょっとシックな感じもあって。
The logo this time is so cute. It's got a bit of a chic feel too.
そうなんだよ、ちょっとウェディングっぽい感じっていうのかな。 / あ、可愛い！っぽい！
Yeah, it's got a bit of a wedding vibe, I guess? / Oh, cute! It really does!
なんかお菓子みたいなイメージだね。 / そうだね、ケーキも後ろにあるしね。
It kind of looks like sweets. / Yeah, and there's a cake in the back too.
お、お城すごいね、あれね。 / イエーイ！
Whoa, that castle is incredible. / Yay!
ちょっと今見えてないけど... イエーイ！
I can't see it right now, but... Yay!
おぉー。
Ooh.
ちょっとね、これからもね、大先輩なんですけど...
Well, you see, going forward... even though you're a major senpai...
ちょっと、これ何ですか？
Hey, what are you doing?
ゴマすってる、これ。 / えー、すってないですよ！
You're buttering me up, aren't you? / No, I'm not!
いや、でもね、これからもよろしくお願いします、よろしくお願いしますよー。
No, but seriously, I look forward to working with you from now on!
はい、後輩としてよろしくね。あー、ありがとう、よろしくねー。
Alright, as my kouhai, I count on you. Thanks, looking forward to it!
じゃあ、メル先輩、まだこれからいーっぱいあると思うので。 / ありますとも、まだまだ！
Well, Mel-senpai, I'm sure there's lots more to come today. / You bet there is, plenty more!
帰りましょうかね、じゃあ。 / え？帰るの？
Guess I'll head home then. / Huh? You're going home?
頑張って、頑張って！ / ありがとう！
Good luck, do your best! / Thanks!
ちょちょちょ、待て待て待て！おいおいおい、なになに！
Wait, wait, wait! Hey, hey, hey, what are you doing?!
まだ帰さないよ！ / きゃっ！
I'm not letting you go home yet! / Eek!
上杉君！ 100点！ 風太郎君！ 嘘じゃない！ 起きて！
Uesugi-kun! 100 points! Fuutaro-kun! It's not a lie! Wake up!
喜びも (喜びも)
Joy (Joy)
悲しみも (悲しみも) あなたさえ
Sadness (Sadness), even you
五等分なんです
Are divided into five equal parts
一つ、作り笑いも見抜かれ
One, you even see through my fake smile.
二つ、あんたなんか大嫌いよ
Two, I totally hate you.
三つ、真っ直ぐなこの気持ち、気づいて
Three, these straightforward feelings, notice them.
四つ、気がつくとだんだん
Four, before I knew it, bit by bit...
五つ、分かり合えたね
Five, we came to understand each other.
勉強だけじゃなくて、君を知りたいよ
It's not just about studying, I want to know you.
大嫌いから大好きへと
From 'I hate you' to 'I love you'...
変わる心についていけないよ
I can't keep up with my changing heart.
どんなこともあなたさえ
No matter what happens, even you...
五等分です、でも私、私、私、私、私...
Are one-fifth, but I, I, I, I, I...
私たちは
We are,
we are,
あなたが、好きよ
we love you.
少し複雑に心の中
The inside of my heart is a little complicated,
でも変わってゆく気持ち
but these changing feelings...
ずっとこんな関係続いたらいいのにな
I wish this relationship could last forever.
忘れられない思い出も
Even the unforgettable memories,
これから増えるストーリーも
and the stories that will grow from here on,
あなたなしだったら意味がない、だめよ
would be meaningless without you; that just won't do.
ずっと側で
Always stay by my side,
教えてね
and tell me things, okay?
だけど勝手に胸の鼓動、高鳴る
But my heart starts racing all on its own.
運命だって
I can even believe
信じられる
in something like fate.
同じ気持ちで
With these same feelings,
またいつか いつか いつか いつかいつか
someday, someday, someday, someday, someday...
正夢に見るから
It'll become a dream come true.
少しずつ変わる思い
These slowly changing thoughts,
焦りやいらだち和らいでく
the impatience and irritation are softening.
信じきれる自信
The confidence to fully believe...
胸の奥に隠れてる言葉
The words hidden deep in my chest,
例え下手だけどいいですか
is it okay even if I'm not good at expressing them?
私ついてゆくわ
I will follow you.
いつまでも
Forever,
忘れない
I won't forget.
出会えた奇跡、偶然じゃない そうでしょ
The miracle of our meeting wasn't a coincidence, right?
大嫌いから
From 'I hate you'
大好きへと
to 'I love you',
変わる心について行きたいよ
I want to follow my changing heart.
どんなことも
Whatever happens,
あなたさえ
as long as I have you,
言葉は不要です
no words are necessary.
でも私 私 私 私 私 私
But I, I, I, I, I, I,
ずっと ずっと ずっと あなたに
always, always, always to you...
愛を誓います
I vow my love.
イェーイ！
Yeeeaaay!
メルちゃんおめでとう！
ありがとうー！サンキューサンキュー！
Congratulations Mel-chan!
Thank you! Thank you, thank you!
すごい！この曲あれか！
「五等分の花嫁」の曲だ！
Amazing! This song is that one!
It's the song from "The Quintessential Quintuplets"!
そうなんだよー！
That's right!
どうして今日この5人で集められたか
みんなわかる？
Do you all know why
we five gathered here today?
えー、なんでなんで？
わかんない！わかんないかー。
Eh, why why?
We don't know! You don't know, huh?
頭を見るんだ！
Look at our heads!
あたま？ヘッド？ヘッド？
Heads? Headphones? Headphones?
ゴールデンヘッド！
Golden headphones!
ゴールデンヘッド！おそろい！すごーい！
Golden headphones! Matching! Amazing!
そこも5人でねメルだから歌いたかったんだ！
Since there's five of us, I really wanted to sing this!
おー、嬉しい！やったー！
Oh, I'm so happy! Yay!
ってことはさ、でもこの曲だと、
私たちの中から1人選んでもらわなきゃいけないんじゃないの？
But if we're doing this song,
doesn't that mean you have to pick one of us?
確かに！そうだよね！選ばなきゃ！
True! That's right! You have to choose!
ちょっとちょっとちょっとー！
今日は5周年なんだからー！
Wait, wait, wait!
Today is my 5th anniversary!
メルの特権！
It's Mel's special privilege!
メルがナンバーワンってこと！
It means Mel is number one!
えー！やだやだやだー！
私を選んで！私の心！
Ehh! No, no, no!
Pick me! My heart!
待って待って！入れて入れて！
私こそナンバーワン！
Wait, wait! Let me in!
I'm the true number one!
お待たせ！遅くなってごめんね
Sorry to keep you waiting! Sorry I'm late.
大丈夫だよ！今日はなにしてたの？
It's okay! What were you doing today?
今日はね！ちょこ先生とねねちと〜
Today, you see! I was with Choco-sensei and Nenechi...
ってことがあってさ！めっちゃ楽しかったよ！
...and that happened! It was so much fun!
(楽しそうに話すメルを見て微笑ましい反面、少しもやもやした感情になってしまった。)
(Seeing Mel talk so happily is heartwarming, but at the same time, I felt a bit of a hazy feeling.)
(せっかく時間を作ってくれてるのにこんなんじゃだめだな)
(She's gone to the trouble of making time for me, I shouldn't be like this.)
んー？なんかあった？
Hmm? Did something happen?
(うまく隠してたつもりだったけどどうやら気づかれたようだった。)
(I thought I was hiding it well, but it seems she noticed.)
(なんでわかるんだろう…)
(How does she know...?)
えっな、なんで？
Eh, wha, why?
そりゃあ君のことちゃーんと見てますから！わかるよ？
That's because I'm watching you closely! Of course I know.
…いや、その。僕といるときもちゃんと楽しめてるのかなって…
...No, well. I was wondering if you're actually enjoying yourself when you're with me...
もう！楽しいに決まってるでしょ！
じゃなかったらこんなおしゃれして…
Geez! Of course I'm having fun!
If I weren't, I wouldn't have dressed up like this...
一週間前からずっと楽しみになんかしらてないってば！
and I wouldn't have been looking forward to this for a whole week!
(頬を膨らませて怒るメルを見て不謹慎だけど僕は安心した。)
(It was improper of me, but seeing Mel puff out her cheeks in annoyance made me feel relieved.)
（頬を膨らませて怒るメルを見て不謹慎だけど僕は安心した。）
(Seeing Mel puffing out her cheeks in anger, though it's inappropriate, I felt relieved.)
ていうか君もそういうこと考えるんだね
Come to think of it, you think about those things too.
え？
Eh?
ううん、いつもそういうの隠すからさ！
No, I mean, you always hide that kind of thing!
ふふ、可愛いところあるね～
Hehe, you have a cute side.
あのさ、この間ドレス着てみたいっていってたよね。本当に着てみない？
Hey, you said you wanted to try wearing a dress the other day. Do you really want to try it on?
えっ！？着れるの…？！！！
Eh?! I can wear it...?!!!
Wishing
作詞・作曲：ヒゲドライバー
Lyrics/Composition: Hige Driver
朝になったら
When morning comes
二人目を合わせて
The two of us will meet eyes
たわいないこと
Silly little things
少し話したいな
I want to talk for a bit
晴れた午後は
On a sunny afternoon
そっと手をつないで
Gently holding hands
穏やかな街を
Through the peaceful town
少し歩いてみたり
We might walk for a bit
そんな想像さえ
Even just that imagination
愛おしくて
Is so precious
いつまでも同じ時間を
I want to spend the same time
一緒に過ごしていたくて
Together forever
だって朝も夜も
Because morning and night
伝えたいことたくさんあって
There are so many things I want to tell you
今日を明日も
Today and tomorrow
好きだなんて言えたら
If only I could say I love you
夜になったら
When night comes
星の見える場所で
In a place where stars are visible
眠りにつくまで
Until we fall asleep
ずっと寄り添っていたいな
I want to stay close forever
触れられる距離が
The distance where I can touch you
愛おしくて
Is so precious
その声をその体温を
That voice, that warmth
もっと感じていたくて
I want to feel them more
だって何度も何度も
Because no matter how many times
名前を呼んでもまだ足りなくて
I call your name, it's still not enough
今日を明日も
Today and tomorrow
そう二人でいれたら
If only the two of us could be together
切ないときは
When I feel lonely
綺麗な花を飾りましょう
Let's decorate with beautiful flowers
悲しいときは
When I'm sad
楽しい話をしましょう
Let's talk about happy things
･･･そう
...So
髪に
In my hair
頬に
On my cheeks
ただ伝わってくれるだけで
Just by letting it reach you
暗い
The dark
心も
Heart too
瞬間明るくなるんだって
Will brighten up in an instant
朝も
The morning too
夜も
The night too
叶えたいことこんなにあって
There are so many things I want to fulfill
今日も
Today too
明日も
Tomorrow too
幸せだと
That I'm happy
あぁ言えたら
Ah, if I could say it
いいのに
It would be nice
メルは、あなたのことを愛しています
Mel loves you.
みんなー！ここまで歌ってきましたけど、
Everyone! I've been singing up to this point,
どうですか？楽しんでますかー？
how is it? Are you enjoying yourselves?
ここで恒例の、みんなお待ちかね、グッズタイムに行きたいと思います！
Now, it's time for the usual Goods Time that everyone's been waiting for!
もう5年目になるので、みんなも大体流れは分かってきたよね？
It's already the 5th year, so everyone probably knows the drill by now, right?
そう、正解！なんと、この後、
Yes, that's right! Surprisingly, after this,
夜空メル5周年グッズが、販売されます！
Yozora Mel 5th Anniversary merchandise will go on sale!
うぉーやったー！イェイイェイイェーイ！
Whoo, we did it! Yay yay yay!
まず一つ目は、さとうぽて先生描き下ろし、
First up is illustrated by Sato Pote-sensei,
アクリルジオラマスタンド！ドドドーン！
the acrylic diorama stand! Ta-da!
なんと、このアクリルスタンド、ゆらゆら揺れるようになっております！
Surprisingly, this acrylic stand is designed to sway back and forth!
すごい！可愛いよー
Amazing! It's so cute.
それからね、純白のドレス、めちゃくちゃ可愛いので、ぜひゲットしてください！
Also, the pure white dress is incredibly cute, so please make sure to get it!
そして、二つ目！は、ミシュネ先生描き下ろしの、メルと始める新生活クッション！
And second! Is the 'New Life with Mel Cushion' illustrated by Mishune-sensei!
表裏どちらもガチ恋距離のメルちゃんがいます。
On both sides, Mel-chan is at a 'serious love distance'.
お好みで使ってください。
Please use it as you like.
君の生活の一部にメルを置いてくれると嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if you make Mel a part of your daily life.
そして、三つ目！メルと契約ネックレスです！
And third! The 'Contract Necklace with Mel'!
アクセサリー物は実はメル初めてなので、ぜひこれを付けてほしいな。
Actually, this is Mel's first time doing an accessory, so I really want you to wear it.
男の子も女の子も着けやすいデザインにメルが監修させていただきました！イェイ！どや！
Mel supervised the design to make it easy for both boys and girls to wear! Yay!
これ後ね、みんな気づいたかな？今回のメインイラスト、実はメル付けてるんだ。
By the way, did everyone notice? In the main illustration, Mel is actually wearing it.
なので、これを付ければメルとお揃い！
So, if you wear it, we'll be matching!
そしてメルとずっと一緒にいるよっていう契約も結んだことになるので、ぜひこちらもゲットしてください！
And it means we've made a contract to be together forever, so please get this one too!
そして、フルセットで購入してくれた方には、メルの直筆サインが入ったポストカードがもらえます！
And for those who purchase the full set, you'll receive a postcard with Mel's handwritten signature!
やったー！複製メッセージも付いてますので、こちらもね、お早めに。
Yay! It also comes with a printed message, so please get this one early too.
数量限定になってるので、お早めにお願いしますね。
Since it's limited quantity, please be quick.
グッズはこの後、21時から販売されます。
The merchandise will go on sale after this, from 21:00.
心を込めて、今回もカキカキしますので、よろしくお願いします。
I'll be signing them with all my heart this time too, so please look forward to it.
それではね、次の曲で最後になるんですが、しかーし！
Now, the next song will be the last one, but!
今回もメンバー限定でアフターライブを開催しちゃいます！やったー！
This time too, we'll be holding an after-live exclusively for members! Yay!
よかったらお前もカプ民にならないか？
If you'd like, why don't you become a Kapu-min too?
なので、今のうちにメンバー登録もよろしくお願いします！
So, please consider joining the membership while you can!
あっという間のライブでしたけど、5年目ももっともっといろんな人が楽しんで、
It was a short live, but in the 5th year, I'll work hard so even more people can enjoy,
メルのことを好きになってくれるように、ホロライブを引っ張っていけるように頑張りますので、
and come to love Mel, and so I can help lead Hololive,
これからもよろしくお願いします！
so please keep supporting me!
だけど、
But,
これからもよろしくお願いします。
please continue to support me.
みんなのことが好きな気持ちを最後まで込めて、
I'll pour all my feelings of love for everyone into it until the very end,
次の曲歌います。
as I sing the next song.
合いの手もよろしくお願いします！
Please join in with the calls too!
はい、3, 2, 1!
Alright, 3, 2, 1!
...ねえ、どうかな？似合ってる？
...Hey, what do you think? Does it look good?
うん、綺麗だよ
Yeah, you look beautiful.
ふふーん、ありがと！でもまさかこんな早く着れるとはな〜！
Hehe, thanks! But I never thought I'd get to wear it this soon!
写真だけだけどね...
It's only for a photo, though...
いやーまさかメルプロポーズされたのかと思っちゃったよ！
Man, I thought for a second that Mel was being proposed to!
いつか...ね
Someday... right?
ん？なんか言った？
Hmm? Did you say something?
いや！なんでもない
No! It's nothing.
（やっぱりメルは深夜アニメの主人公なのかもしれない。）
[I knew it, Mel might really be a late-night anime protagonist.]
あ、そうだ。お礼に...これ受け取ってほしいな
Oh, right. In return... I want you to have this.
え？これは...？
Eh? This is...?
これはね、代々伝わる大切な人に渡すネックレスだよ。
This is a necklace passed down through generations to be given to someone precious.
メルとずっと一緒にいる契を結んだ者だけがつけることができるのだよ！
Only those who have made a vow to stay with Mel forever can wear it!
なにそれこわ！！ていうか中二病感すごいんだけど！？
What the heck, that's scary!! I mean, the chuunibyou vibes are intense!?
うるさい！！！！ていうか！いるのいらないの！？どっち！
Shut up!!!! I mean! Do you want it or not!? Which is it!
...うん、ありがとう。ありがたく受け取らせていただきます
...Yeah, thank you. I'll gratefully accept it.
よろしい。メルとおそろいだよ！
Good. Now we match!
これからもこんな私だけどよろしくね。大好きだよ
Please keep putting up with me. I love you.
メルは少し照れながらかしこまった口調で微笑んだ。
Mel smiled with a shy but formal tone.
デート誘ってだって
Even if you ask me out on a date
浮気したって
Even if I cheated
子供じゃないんだし
I'm not a child anymore
秘密くらいあるよ
So I have a secret or two
全部なんて 見せてちゃ続かない
If I show you everything, it won't last
ケンカしてても 隣で寝ること
Even if we fight, we'll sleep side by side
これからの 約束ね
That's a promise for the future
返事！ (はい！)
Answer! (Yes!)
いくつになっても 恋させてよ あなたに
No matter how old we get, let me stay in love with you
かっこいいとこは 見ないようにしてあげるね
I'll try not to look at your cool side
曖昧だけど 恋していて 私に
It's ambiguous, but please stay in love with me
綺麗だね 言われるように 頑張るから ねっ
I'll do my best so you'll tell me I'm beautiful, okay?
嫌なことがあった日
On days when bad things happened
下手な料理で 笑顔をありがとう
Thank you for the smile over my clumsy cooking
合わない趣味ばかり
We have nothing but mismatched hobbies
もっと教えて こないだの続き
Tell me more, pick up where we left off
家族増えても 恋人がいいの
Even if our family grows, I want us to be lovers
お互いも 増やしてよ
Let's increase our love for each other too
返事！ (はい！)
Answer! (Yes!)
いくつになっても デートしてよ 記念日
No matter how old we get, let's go on dates on anniversaries
プレゼントはいらない ほら おしゃれしてね
I don't need a present, just look sharp, okay?
晴れもいいけど 雨の日には くっついて
Sunny days are nice, but on rainy days, let's snuggle
一つの傘 揺らしながら 虹を待つの
While swaying under one umbrella, we'll wait for the rainbow
いびきかいた
You were snoring
寝てる隙に
While you were asleep
ほっぺにそっと
Gently on your cheek
キスしてること
I gave you a kiss
気づかなかった
You didn't notice
寝てる隙に
While you were asleep
続けてくれてた
You kept on sleeping
Mr.ダーリン
Mr. Darling
しわが増えても
Even if I get more wrinkles
甘えたいんだよ
I want to be pampered
もちろん手をつなぐこと
And of course, holding hands
返事、はい！
Answer me, "Yes!"
いくつになっても
No matter how old we get,
飽きないでね お願い
don't get bored of me, please
嫉妬しちゃうけど
I might get a bit jealous, but
頭撫でて 慰めてね
pet my head and comfort me
いつまでもずっと
Forever and always,
恋していて 私に
keep falling in love with me
綺麗だね 言われるように
So that you'll tell me I'm beautiful,
頑張るからね
I'll do my very best
みんなのおかげで5周年を迎えられたよ！
Thanks to everyone, I celebrated my 5th anniversary!
これからもたくさんの楽しい思い出つくっていこうね♡
Let's keep making many fun memories together ♡
BIG LOVE♡だいすき！！
BIG LOVE ♡ I love you!!
みんなのおかげで5周年を迎えられたよ！
Thanks to everyone, I've reached my 5th anniversary!
これからもたくさんの楽しい思い出つくっていこうね♡
Let's keep making lots of fun memories together from now on ♡
BIG LOVE♡だいすき!! ♡Mel♡
BIG LOVE♡ I love you!! ♡Mel♡